(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T22:15:30.827623",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss."
今 気付いた想い
My feelings that I just realized
どんな言葉でも足りないから
are too big for any words alone.
1, 2, 3, 4!
当たり前すぎるぐらい
It's so natural,
友達の時間長かったせいで
because we've been friends for so long.
あなたの癖や性格だって
I know your habits and quirks
他の子より知ってんの
better than anyone else does.
はぁ〜 意気地なしで恥ずかしがり屋な
Ah~ You're such a shy coward,
あなたをもう待っていられないの!
I can't wait for you anymore!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss."
今さら「好き」なんて言葉より
Rather than just saying "I like you" now,
キメあるでしょ?
isn't this more striking?
あなたにだけはそっと教えてあげる
I'll gently tell only you
胸の奥 小さいつぼみのぬくもり
the warmth of the little bud in my heart.
時々甘えてみたり 拗ねてみたり
Sometimes acting spoiled, sometimes sulking—
そんな作戦らしくない
that doesn't sound like my strategy at all.
か弱きオトメじゃ勝てないの
A delicate maiden can't win you over,
この恋だけは負けらんない
and I cannot lose this love.
はぁ〜 鈍感なあなたのこと
Ah~ Since you're so dense,
振り向かせたいから勝負かけるの!
I'm taking a gamble to turn your head!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss."
「愛しています」なんて言葉より
Rather than words like "I love you,"
魅力的でしょ?
isn't it more attractive?
聞こえちゃうくらい早くなるドキドキ
My heart beats so fast you might hear it.
初恋はサイダーみたいに弾ける
First love fizzes and pops like cider.
“友達同士” そんな境界線
The boundary line of "just friends"—
今すぐに飛び越えたいの
I want to leap right across it now!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss."
今さら「好き」なんて言葉より
Rather than just saying "I like you" now,
キメあるでしょ?
isn't this more striking?
あなたにだけはそっと教えてあげる
I'll gently tell only you
胸の奥 小さいつぼみのぬくもり
the warmth of the little bud in my heart.
感じて
Feel it.
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss"
今 気付いた 想い
I just realized my love,
どんな 言葉 でも 足りない から
that is beyond words.
1, 2, 3, 4!
当たり前 すぎる ぐらい
It's way too obvious
友達 の 時間 が 長かった せいで
since we've been longtime friends.
あなた の クセ や 性格 だって
All of your personality quirks,
他 の 子 より 知ってんの
I know them better than the other girls.
ha〜 意地悪 で 恥ずかしがり屋 な
Ah, you're a shy coward—
あなた を もう 待って らんない の!
I can't wait for you anymore!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss"
今さら 「好き」 なんて 言葉 より
Would send a clearer message
キキメ ある でしょ?
than words like "I like you".
あなたにだけは そっと教えてあげる
I want to gently tell only you
胸 の 奥 小さな つぼみ の ぬくもり
the warmth of the little bud growing in my heart.
時々 甘えて みたり 拗ねて みたり
Sometimes to depend on you or to sulk,
そんな 作戦 らしく ない
it's not like me to do that.
気弱 な オトメ じゃ 勝て ない の
Such a delicate maiden won't get you.
この 恋 だけ は 負け らん ない
I must not lose this love!
ha〜 鈍感 な あなた の こと
Ah, as I want an insensitive fellow to notice me,
振り向かせたいから勝負かけるの!
I'll take a gamble on you!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss"
どっち が 好き な の よ !
Which one do you like?!
(なんとか なんじゃないかな love it love it)
(Can't we somehow... love it love it)
なんとかなんないかな？
Can't we somehow work it out?
隣のあいつが邪魔だな
That guy next to us is in the way!
行くぜ！そんなこと
Let's go! No way!
ダメダメダメ 先手必勝絶対
No way, preemptive strike is absolute!
とわとは違うな なんだって競争 苦手だそういうの
Wait, what's with this competition, I hate that sort of thing.
なんだかさみしい 気持ちはチモシー
Somehow this lonely feeling is a secret.
連れて知って パレパレとスケルトン
Let me show! Palpable, palette, skeleton.
あの娘にゃ負けない 毛羽立ってジェラシー
I won't lose to her, bristling with jealousy!
欲張りめ！横取りか？
You greedy thing! Trying to snatch him?
言わなきゃってわかってる
I know I have to say it,
あでもないこうでもない やめにしましょう
let's stop all these hesitation and excuses.
つらぬけ my my my mind
Push through, my my my mind!
聞きたくない！ いいわけバニー
I don't want to hear it! Iiwake Bunny.
地団駄no! 優柔不断だんだん
Stamping my feet, no! Indecisive step by step.
ハニーバニー だりーだりーな
Honey bunny, I'm getting so lazy.
マジな話 どっちが好きなのよ！
Seriously speaking, which one do you like?!
(ダメダメダメ) よそみしないで
(No, no, no) Don't look away!
(ダメダメダメ) もう逃げ出したいのは私のほう
(No, no, no) I'm the one who wants to run away!
通しません！ 反対方向 wanted! いいわけバニー
I won't let you pass! Opposite direction, wanted! Iiwake Bunny.
大都会は大得意？ 興味がねーから超ネガティブ
Great at the big city? Not interested, super negative.
人混みキミ探す 張り紙
Searching for you in the crowd, missing poster.
とどけ意気込み！ 嫉妬はたしなみ 荒ぶってポエミー
Deliver my enthusiasm! Jealousy is a hobby, running wild poetically.
前進あるのみ トラブルってエネミー
Forward motion only, trouble is the enemy.
疲れちゃった一休み なんとかねやってよネ明日の私
I'm tired, let's take a break. Do something about it tomorrow, me!
まかせろ my my my mind
Leave it to my my my mind!
決められない！ いいわけバニー
I can't decide! Iiwake Bunny.
うやむやyes! 唯我独尊そんそん
Vague, yes! Sole and supreme, son son.
メニーメニーマニーマニー ガチな話ハウマッチ？
Many many many many, seriously, how much?
オトシマエ 朝飯前です
Settling accounts is a piece of cake.
そんなのってない！ 私一途なほう my sweet 逃がさない
That's not fair! I'm the devoted one, my sweet, I won't let you escape.
どこへだって行けばいい いいわけない！
Go wherever you want! No way!
容赦しない 冗談じゃない
No mercy, no joking!
ぶつけろ my my my mind
Let it out, my my my mind!
聞きたくない！ いいわけバニー
I don't want to hear it! Iiwake Bunny.
地団駄no! 優柔不断だんだん
Stamping my feet, no! Indecisive step by step.
ハニーバニー だりーだりーな マジな話どっちが好きなのよ！
Honey bunny, I'm getting so lazy. Seriously, which one do you like?!
疲れちゃった人休み なんとかねやってよネ明日の私
A tired person's break, do something about it tomorrow, me!
まかせろ my my my mind
Leave it to my my my mind!
決められない！ いいわけバニー
I can't decide! Iiwake Bunny.
うやむやyes! 唯我独尊そんそん
Vague, yes! Sole and supreme, son son.
メニーメニーマニーマニー ガチな話ハウマッチ？
Many many many many, seriously, how much?
オトシマエ 朝飯前です
Settling accounts is a piece of cake.
そんなのってない！ 私一途なほう my sweet 逃がさない
That's not fair! I'm the devoted one, my sweet, I won't let you escape.
どこへだって行けばいい いいわけない！
Go wherever you want! No way!
容赦しない 冗談じゃない
No mercy, no joking!
ぶつけろ my my my mind
Let it out, my my my mind!
聞きたくない！ いいわけバニー
I don't want to hear it! Iiwake Bunny.
地団駄no! 優柔不断だんだん
Stamping my feet, no! Indecisive step by step.
ハニーバニー だりーだりーな マジな話どっちが好きなのよ！
Honey bunny, I'm getting so lazy. Seriously, which one do you like?!
どこへだって行けばいい いいわけない！
Go wherever you want! No way!
容赦しない 冗談じゃない
No mercy, no joking!
ぶつけろ my my my mind
Let it out, my my my mind!
聞きたくない！ いいわけバニー
I don't want to hear it! Iiwake Bunny.
地団駄no! 優柔不断だんだん
Stamping my feet, no! Indecisive step by step.
ハニーバニー だりーだりーな マジな話どっちが好きなのよ！
Honey bunny, I'm getting so lazy. Seriously, which one do you like?!
よそみしないで もう逃げ出したいけどやるしかない
Don't look away! I want to run away, but I have to do it!
通しません！ 反対方向 wanted! いいわけバニー
I won't let you pass! Opposite direction, wanted! Iiwake Bunny.
そばにいていいわけバニー
Stay by my side, Iiwake Bunny.
はいってわけで、1曲目は初恋サイダー、そして2曲目はいいわけバニー！
So that's it! The first song was "Hatsukoi Cider", and the second song was "Iiwake Bunny!"
みんな、どうぺこか？
Everyone having fun?
楽しんでくれているぺこか？
Are you enjoying yourselves, Peko?
ぺこらの3周年ライブ、楽しみに待っていてね！じゃあ、早速行ってみよう！バイバーイ！
Pekora's 3rd Anniversary Live! Let's get right into it!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
君がいた夏は
The summer when you were there
遠い夢の中空に消えていった
disappeared into the distant sky like a dream.
打ち上げ花火、打ち明け花火
Fireworks shooting up.
君の髪の香り…
The scent of your hair...
浴衣姿がまぶしすぎて
You looked so dazzling in your yukata.
お祭りの夜は胸がさわいだよ
The festival night made my heart race.
はぐれそうない人ごみの中「はなれないで」と出しかけた手を
In the bustling crowd, I tried to hold out my hand, saying, "Let's not get lost,"
ポケットに入れて握りしめていた
but I clenched it in my pocket instead.
君がいた夏は遠い夢の中空に消えていった
The summer when you were there disappeared into the distant sky like a dream.
打ち上げ花火
Fireworks shooting up.
グレーな雲が流れたら
When the gray clouds drift away,
この空が泣き止んだら
and this sky stops crying,
君の声で目を覚ます
I'll wake up to your voice,
ちょっと長めの眠りから
from a slightly long sleep.
飛立つ季節を待って
Waiting for the season to take flight,
「青い空を共に行こうよ
"Let's go together across the blue sky,
白い砂浜を見下ろしながら
looking down on the white sandy beach.
難しい話はいらない君が笑ってくれればいい」
No need for serious talk; I just want you to smile."
「青い空を共に行こうよ
"Let's go together across the blue sky,
どこへたどり着くんだとしても
wherever we may arrive,
もしも傷を負ったその時は僕の翼を君にあげる」
if ever we get hurt, I'll give you my wings."
そう言って君は少し泣いた
You said that and cried a little.
ララララララララ
La la la...
まぶしい太陽のキラメキの中で
In the dazzling sun's shimmer,
とびきり熱いままで恋をしたいよ
I want to fall in love, as passionately as ever.
世界で一番大好きなあなたが
You are the one I love most in the world,
あたしの一番大切な人だよ
and the most precious person to me.
その手をどんなときも信じているのは
I want to believe in your hand no matter what.
あたしひとりだけだよ
You're the only one.
抱きしめていて
Hug me tight.
強い日差しをやっと連れて来たよ
The strong sunlight has finally arrived.
前に広がる海が眩しくて
The sea stretching out before me is so dazzling,
この手を翳せば 光の魚たちが飛び跳ねている
if I shade my eyes, schools of light fish leap out.
(今年の水着はどう?)
(How is this year's swimsuit?)
いたずらっぽく君に聞かれたけれど
You asked me playfully,
(何か恥ずかしくて)
(though feeling somewhat embarrassed)
視線外して 動揺隠しながら 声が上ずる
I averted my gaze, hiding my flurry as my voice squeaked.
(おいで) 君に好きだと言おう
(Come on) I'll tell you I like you.
(おいで) 言葉にしないと伝わらない
(Come on) Unless I put it into words, it won't get across.
(おいで) 季節なんて過ぎてしまうんだ
(Come on) The seasons will just pass us by.
(おいで) 友達のままじゃいられない
(Come on) We can't stay just friends.
(おいで) 胸の奥が熱くなる
(Come on) Deep in my chest, it gets so hot.
道は突然 二手にいく
The path suddenly splits in two.
baby baby 今が
baby baby Right now,
夢中の真っ最中
right in the middle of our craze.
ドキな笑顔に
With a beating smile,
乙女たちもそぞろ
even the maidens are restless.
男たちの心を
The hearts of the boys
奪うたびに本当へ
every time you steal them, towards reality,
綺麗になってくね
you're becoming more beautiful.
夏の罪は素敵すぎる
Summer's sins are far too wonderful.
空の入道雲がやけにもっさいていたけど
Though the cumulonimbus clouds in the sky looked quite shabby,
強い日差しをやっと連れて来たよ
the strong sunlight has finally arrived.
前に広がる海が眩しくて
The sea stretching out before me is so dazzling,
この手を翳せば 光の魚たちが飛び跳ねている
if I shade my eyes, schools of light fish leap out.
(今年の水着はどう?)
(How is this year's swimsuit?)
いたずらっぽく君に聞かれたけれど
You asked me playfully,
旅立とう 冒険 そしてインドアの神話へ
Let's set off on an adventure, and into indoor mythology—
最大級のラララララ ラビット!!
The ultimate Ra Ra Ra Rabbit!!
最序盤のスライムにビビるのが大概なマイライフ
Getting spooked by an early-game slime is pretty much my my-life
ワン・トゥ・スリーで繋がったセカイに愛があふれ出す
In a world connected by one, two, three, love overflows.
8bitに感じるドキドキ
The pounding feeling in 8-bit,
2Dのラヴじゃダメですか?
isn't 2D love okay?
運ゲー状態ふざんじじゃないぞ
This RNG state is no joke!
レベルアップして超えてやりあえ!
Level up and push past it!
夢に見えてるファンファーレの音
The fanfare sound I see in my dreams,
乱数調整 一転攻勢
RNG adjustment, a sudden reversal,
一点突破 想定外もロマンスの過程
breakthrough on a single point, even the unexpected is part of romance—
ラヴィ ラヴィ ちいさなビートで でっかいアイを交信中!
Lavi lavi, communicating huge love with a tiny beat!
ちょっと沼っても許してね? いつだって愛は非効率!
Forgive me if I get a little hooked, love is always inefficient!
jumpin' jumpin' 弾けるハートを 捕まえておいてね!
jumpin' jumpin' Catch my bouncing heart and hold on to it!
二兎なんて追わないで トゥルーエンドになるまで
Don't chase two hares, until we reach the true end.
最大級のラララララ ラビット!!
The ultimate Ra Ra Ra Rabbit!!
人生とかけて無理ゲーと解く
Likening life to an impossible game,
このラヴって状態異常をとく
solving this love-as-status-ailment.
アイテムはどこで買えますか!?
Where can I buy items!?
救済も! 説明も!
Salvation! Explanation!
足らない! クソゲー!!
Not enough! Crappy game!!
いや、足りないのはわたしのINT!?
No, what's not enough is my INT!?
まあ、どんな難所も 超えてやってるけど
Well, I'll overcome any difficult spot, but
そのまえに誰かいい案ありますか?
does anyone have a good idea before that?
ちゃんと届いている あなたのエール
Your cheering reaches me properly,
一進一退 四面楚歌
one step forward, one step back, beset on all sides,
絶体絶命 大失敗もサクセスの序章
absolute crisis and big failures are the prologue to success—
ラヴィ ラヴィ ちいさなビートで でっかいセカイ躍進中!
Lavi lavi, advancing into a huge world with a tiny beat!
うまくいかないプレイも キミのハートを盗めるのなら
Even a botched play, if it steals your heart,
ドキさせられてたら このまま溺れちゃうよ
if it keeps making my heart pound, I'll drown in it just like this!
エンジェル アラモード
Angel à la mode,
ドキドキ キュンキュン
dokidoki kyunkyun,
夢中にさせてね
let me be obsessed.
その笑顔 キミを見上げたら
That smile, when I look up at you,
眩しすぎて やっぱり好きでした
it's too dazzling, I really did love you.
最大級のラララララ ラビット!!
The ultimate Ra Ra Ra Rabbit!!
最序盤のスライムにビビるのが大概なマイライフ
Getting spooked by an early-game slime is pretty much my my-life
ワン・トゥ・スリーで繋がったセカイに愛があふれ出す
In a world connected by one, two, three, love overflows.
8bitに感じるドキドキ
The pounding feeling in 8-bit,
2Dのラヴじゃダメですか?
isn't 2D love okay?
運ゲー状態ふざんじじゃないぞ
This RNG state is no joke!
レベルアップして超えてやりあえ!
Level up and push past it!
夢に見えてるファンファーレの音
The fanfare sound I see in my dreams,
乱数調整 一転攻勢
RNG adjustment, a sudden reversal,
一点突破 想定外もロマンスの過程
breakthrough on a single point, even the unexpected is part of romance—
ラヴィ ラヴィ ちいさなビートで でっかいアイを交信中!
Lavi lavi, communicating huge love with a tiny beat!
ちょっと沼っても許してね? いつだって愛は非効率!
Forgive me if I get a little hooked, love is always inefficient!
jumpin' jumpin' 弾けるハートを 捕まえておいてね!
jumpin' jumpin' Catch my bouncing heart and hold on to it!
二兎なんて追わないで トゥルーエンドになるまで
Don't chase two hares, until we reach the true end.
最大級のラララララ ラビット!!
The ultimate Ra Ra Ra Rabbit!!
人生とかけて無理ゲーと解く
Likening life to an impossible game,
このラヴって状態異常をとく
solving this love-as-status-ailment.
アイテムはどこで買えますか!?
Where can I buy items!?
救済も! 説明も!
Salvation! Explanation!
足らない! クソゲー!!
Not enough! Crappy game!!
いや、足りないのはわたしのINT!?
No, what's not enough is my INT!?
まあ、どんな難所も 超えてやってるけど
Well, I'll overcome any difficult spot, but
そのまえに誰かいい案ありますか?
does anyone have a good idea before that?
ちゃんと届いている あなたのエール
Your cheering reaches me properly,
一進一退 四面楚歌
one step forward, one step back, beset on all sides,
絶体絶命 大失敗もサクセスの序章
absolute crisis and big failures are the prologue to success—
ラヴィ ラヴィ ちいさなビートで でっかいセカイ躍進中!
Lavi lavi, advancing into a huge world with a tiny beat!
うまくいかないプレイも キミのハートを盗めるのなら
Even a botched play, if it steals your heart,
ドキさせられてたら このまま溺れちゃうよ
if it keeps making my heart pound, I'll drown in it just like this!
エンジェル アラモード
Angel à la mode,
ドキドキ キュンキュン
dokidoki kyunkyun,
夢中にさせてね
let me be obsessed.
その笑顔 キミを見上げたら
That smile, when I look up at you,
眩しすぎて やっぱり好きでした
it's too dazzling, I really did love you.
最大級のラララララ ラビット!!
The ultimate Ra Ra Ra Rabbit!!
let's go fever time!（あ-ふぁ♪）
let's go fever time! (Ah-fa♪)
lovely angel☆（chuchu☆chu!）
lovely angel☆ (chuchu☆chu!)
wow!
ave;new paradise
come on!
はるかなた キミに 恋の嵐を 届けます☆
Sending a storm of love to you afar☆
（go！）
(go!)
狙ったもの！ 宝物は 逃げるわけ ないし ♪
The treasure I've targeted is bound to be caught♪
姫森来てくれてありがとねー！
Thanks for coming, Luna!
ぺこらぺこら先輩3周年おめでとうー！
Congratulations on your 3rd anniversary, Pekora-senpai!
ありがとうのじゃー！
Thank you so much-nanora!
さすがにさ、寂しいぺこじゃん
It's pretty lonely without you, peko-jan.
1年に1度しか会えないこんなぺこだったら
If it's only once a year like this, peko...
1年ぶりなんだよね
It's been a whole year, huh.
そうそれぐらいなんだよね
That's right, about a year.
ちょっと、あまりにもさ、てぇてぇからビックリ忍者みたく嫌われてるワンチャン
Wait, it's so overwhelmingly precious I'm surprised, maybe you secretly hate me?
お餅のぺこじゃないのよ！また来年
It's not a mochi-peko! See you next year!
また来年ー！
See you next year!
いっちぇー の で 君 と だけ ！
On the count of three, just with you!
もう少し眠りたいけど もったいないよ 今日はsunday
I want to sleep a bit more, but it's a waste, today is Sunday.
楽しいことやりたいこと
Fun things, things I want to do,
wake up! 始めようよ
wake up! Let's get started.
めぐりめぐる季節 君と次のステージへ
Turning seasons, heading with you to the next stage.
声を合わせ 扉開けて 駆け出せ 迷わずに
Matching our voices, opening the door, running out without hesitation.
転んでも かっこ悪くても イイじゃない
Even if I stumble or look uncool, isn't that fine?
stand up! イメージもっと重ねて行く その先で
Stand up! Layering images further ahead.
いっちぇー の で 君 と だけ ！
On the count of three, just with you!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて奏でる メロディを
High-touch, clapping hands to play the melody,
合図に走り出せ go! 君となら こわくない
Starting off on the cue, go! With you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手たたいて重ねる そのメモリーは
High-touch, clapping hands together, those memories are
明日へのエナジー yeah! さあ行こうよ もっと先へ
Energy for tomorrow, yeah! Now let's go further ahead.
君となら happy lucky life！
With you, happy lucky life!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて奏でる メロディを
High-touch, clapping hands to play the melody,
合図に走り出せ go! 君となら こわくない
Starting off on the cue, go! With you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手たたいて重ねる そのメモリーは
High-touch, clapping hands together, those memories are
明日へのエナジー yeah! さあ行こうよ もっと先へ
Energy for tomorrow, yeah! Now let's go further ahead.
君となら happy lucky life！
With you, happy lucky life!
あの日見た夢の続き 追いかける その日まで
Chasing the continuation of the dream I saw that day until that moment
涙なんて振り切るくらい もっとスピードアップ
Speeding up even more to shake off any tears
どんな未来になっても 後悔しないよ
No matter what future awaits, I won't regret it.
自分自身 選んだ道 踏み出せ 迷わずに
Stepping out on the path I chose myself without hesitation.
落ち込んで進めなくなった時は wake up!
When you feel down and can't move forward, wake up!
思い出す 夢見た頃の記憶を
Remember the memories from when you dreamed.
手と手で奏でる 叶える 煌めく夢を 君とだけ！
Clapping hand in hand, realizing that sparkling dream, just with you!
ハイタッチ その度に繋がっている 心
High-touch, hearts connecting every time
一人じゃないことを そう気付かせてくれたよね
You made me realize I'm not alone.
ハイタッチ 手と手たたいて奏でる そのメロディが
High-touch, playing the melody by clapping hands together
世界に届くまで yeah! この夢は続いてく
Until it reaches the world, yeah! This dream continues.
君となら happy lucky life！
With you, happy lucky life!
くじいて歩けない日は おんぶしてあげる
On days when you're discouraged and can't walk, I'll carry you.
ほら見て そっちの方が強く地面踏み込める
Look, that way we can stomp the ground even firmer.
巡り巡る日々を 辿り 夢見たステージへ
Tracing our turning days, heading to the stage we dreamed of.
届くその日を見つめて起動そう 君とだけ！
Looking forward to the day we reach it, let's start, just with you!
手と手を鳴らす度 小さなビッグバン
Every time we clap our hands, a small Big Bang
無限のそのチカラを受け取って 進め！
Receive that infinite power and move forward!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて奏でる メロディを
High-touch, clapping hands to play the melody,
合図に走り出せ go! 君となら こわくない
Starting off on the cue, go! With you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手たたいて重ねる そのメモリーは
High-touch, clapping hands together, those memories are
明日へのエナジー yeah! さあ行こうよ もっと先へ
Energy for tomorrow, yeah! Now let's go further ahead.
君となら happy lucky life！
With you, happy lucky life!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて奏でる メロディを
High-touch, clapping hands to play the melody,
合図に走り出せ go! 君となら こわくない
Starting off on the cue, go! With you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手たたいて重ねる そのメモリーは
High-touch, clapping hands together, those memories are
明日へのエナジー yeah! さあ行こうよ もっと先へ
Energy for tomorrow, yeah! Now let's go further ahead.
巡り巡る日々を 辿り夢見たステージへ
Tracing our turning days, heading to the stage we dreamed of.
届くその日を見つめて おこそう 君とだけ！
Looking forward to the day we reach it, let's make it happen, just with you!
手と手を鳴らす度 小さなビッグバン
Every time we clap our hands, a small Big Bang
無限のそのチカラを受け取って 進め！
Receive that infinite power and move forward!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて奏でる メロディを
High-touch, clapping hands to play the melody,
合図に走り出せ go! 君となら こわくない
Starting off on the cue, go! With you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手たたいて重ねる そのメモリーは
High-touch, clapping hands together, those memories are
明日へのエナジー yeah! さあ行こうよ もっと先へ
Energy for tomorrow, yeah! Now let's go further ahead.
ハイタッチ 手たたいて奏でる メロディを
High-touch, clapping hands to play the melody,
合図に走り出せ go! 君となら こわくない
Starting off on the cue, go! With you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手たたいて重ねる そのメモリーは
High-touch, clapping hands together, those memories are
明日へのエナジー yeah! さあ行こうよ もっと先へ
Energy for tomorrow, yeah! Now let's go further ahead.
君となら happy lucky life！
With you, happy lucky life!
いっせーので君とだけ！
Just you and me, ready, go!
どこ？そこ？あそこ？見つからないぜっ？
Where? There? Over there? Nowhere to be found?
パパイヤ マンゴー ココ☆ナッツ！
Papaya, mango, Coco☆Nuts!
かき氷 イチゴ味 ベロを出したらまっかっか！
Strawberry shaved ice, show your red tongue!
猛暑 残暑 水着ショー！
Intense heat, late summer heat, swimsuit show!
say！ジャジャジャジャジャジャジャジャーン
Say! Ja-ja-ja-ja-ja-ja-ja-jaan!
ココ☆ナッツ いえい カチカチに燃えているおひさま
Coco☆Nuts yeah, the sun is burning hot!
まっしゅばー ここなつべいべー
Must have Coco Nuts baby!
待ちわびた季節はサマーサマー
The long-awaited season is summer, summer!
まっしゅばー ここなつべいべー
Must have Coco Nuts baby!
思い切って買っちゃったビキニ すごく照れるけど負けないっ！！
I bought a bikini on a whim, I'm so shy but I won't lose!
日焼け止め ココナッツフレーバー
Sunscreen, coconut flavor!
まっしゅばー ここなつべいべー
Must have Coco Nuts baby!
紫外線 トコナッツレーザー
Ultraviolet Toconuts laser!
まっしゅばー ここなつべいべー
Must have Coco Nuts baby!
どっきゅーん ずっきゅーん キミの視線 心臓大爆発☆
Heart-throb, bang! Your gaze makes my heart explode☆
サシスカセ ソココナッツ べいべー
Sa-shi-su-se-so, Coco Nuts baby!
白い砂浜 ココ☆ナッツ いえい
White sandy beach, Coco☆Nuts yeah!
どっきゅーん ずっきゅーん キミの視線
Heart-throb, bang! Your gaze...
心臓 大爆発☆
Heart explosion☆
まっしゅばー ここなつべいべー 白い砂浜 ココ☆ナッツ いえい
Must have Coco Nuts baby, white sandy beach Coco☆Nuts yeah!
さんさんさまーたいむ！いぇい！
Sun sun summer time! Yay!
ココココ ココココ ココナッツ！
Coco-coco-coco-coco-conuts!
まっしゅばー ここなつべいべー 白い砂浜 ココ☆ナッツ いえい
Must have Coco Nuts baby, white sandy beach Coco☆Nuts yeah!
さんさんさまーたいむ！いぇい！
Sun sun summer time! Yay!
かき氷 メロン味 ベロを出したらゾンビだ！ai！
Melon shaved ice, show your tongue and you're a zombie! Ai!
勝負浴衣 着付けて盆 dance！say！
Put on winning yukata for Bon dance! Say!
むしむしうんざり熱帯夜 まっしゅばー ここなつべいべー
Humid and annoying tropical night, must have Coco Nuts baby!
ココナッツジュースみたいな まっしゅばー ここなつべいべー
Like coconut juice, must have Coco Nuts baby!
長ーい夜で 短いサマータイム やってたものがちっ！
Long night, short summer time,finders keepers!
さんさんさまーたいむ！いぇい！
Sun sun summer time! Yay!
まっしゅばー ここなつべいべー 白い砂浜 ココ☆ナッツ いえい
Must have Coco Nuts baby, white sandy beach Coco☆Nuts yeah!
さんさんさまーたいむ！いぇい！
Sun sun summer time! Yay!
ココココ ココココ ココナッツ！
Coco-coco-coco-coco-conuts!
まっしゅばー ここなつべいべー 白い砂浜 ココ☆ナッツ いえい
Must have Coco Nuts baby, white sandy beach Coco☆Nuts yeah!
さんさんさまーたいむ！いぇい！
Sun sun summer time! Yay!
ファイアー！！ス、スパークリング！！
Fire!! S-Sparkling!!
リリリリボンヌ！！フィーバー！！
Ri-ri-ri-ribonne!! Fever!!
ソイヤソイヤソイヤソイヤ！アチアチのサマー 九十九里浜
Soiya soiya soiya soiya! Hot hot summer, Kujukurihama!
アイス 激 アマ キャンプ は さいたま
Ice, super sweet, camping is in Saitama!
まっしゅばー ここなつべいべー 白い砂浜 ココ☆ナッツ いえい
Must have Coco Nuts baby, white sandy beach Coco☆Nuts yeah!
さんさんさまーたいむ！いぇい！
Sun sun summer time! Yay!
ココココ ココココ ココナッツ！
Coco-coco-coco-coco-conuts!
まっしゅばー ここなつべいべー 白い砂浜 ココ☆ナッツ いえい
Must have Coco Nuts baby, white sandy beach Coco☆Nuts yeah!
さんさんさまーたいむ！いぇい！
Sun sun summer time! Yay!
どこ？そこ？あそこ？見つからないぜっ？
Where? There? Over there? Nowhere to be found?
パパイヤ マンゴー ココ☆ナッツ！
Papaya, mango, Coco☆Nuts!
ふたり…あっ、ありがと、ペコちゃん。ありがとう！おめでとう！
Two of... Oh, thank you, Pekora! Thank you! Congratulations!
おめでとう！やった！やったー！
Congratulations! Yay! Yay!
嬉しい！おめでとう！
So happy! Congratulations!
ね、ツーショット撮ってもらおうよ！
Hey, let's get a two-shot photo taken!
で、ポーズどうする？猫のポーズ？
So, what pose? Cat pose?
猫のポーズ。可愛い！
Cat pose. So cute!
ごめんごめん、ちょっとあそこの…
Sorry sorry, over there...
次、次の曲！次の曲！
Next, next song! Next song!
次、いちごいちご！
Next, strawberry strawberry!
ふざけんないよ！
Don't mess with me!
青木、遅いってこ！
Aoki, slow down!
次、しゃくにいくでこ！
Next, let's go to Shaku!
メンタルチェンソー
Mental Chainsaw
ワンツースリーフォー！
1, 2, 3, 4!
打撲だ惨事どんぐりだ三日坊主臭い脳細胞案件じゃん
Battered, tragic, can't be helped, brain cells, case closed
さあ高所バンジー
Now, high-altitude bungee!
アアアアウ！超丸腰メンタル万死？（笑）（笑）（笑）
Ultra round waist, mental 10,000 deaths? (Laughs) (Laughs) (Laughs)
止められない秒針
Unstoppable second hand
アアアアウ！マントマンショアピンの象徴
Mansart, one-man show!
くっだらないのを隠してる遠景仏様はお笑い
Useless follow-ups and envy, you are all show!
アアアアウ！メンタル故障あはんあはんあはんふざけてんな
Empty? Already a mental malfunction? (Laughs) (Laughs) (Laughs)
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓首絞めて
Down, choking down...
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓生きづらいな
Down, hard to live...
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓夢見たって
Down, dreaming...
どう転がっても平凡です居た堪れないぱぁーん
No matter how you roll, it's mediocre, unbearable pa-an!
ウザったきらいだもうイヤイヤイヤってのアイアイヤってもアイアイヤってもアイアイヤパパン
Annoying, dazzling, I've had enough, no!
ウザった限界だもうイヤイヤイヤってのアイアイヤってもアイアイヤって怒号アアアアウ！
Annoying, limit reached, I've had enough, no!
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓吐き捨てんだ
Down, spitting it out...
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓笑えもっと
Down, smile more...
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓落等上等
Down, falling from grace...
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓は？
Down, what?!
ウザったきらいだもうイヤイヤイヤってのアイアイヤってもアイアイヤってもアイアイヤパパン
Annoying, limit reached, I've had enough, no!
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓吐き捨てんだ
Down, spitting it out...
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓笑えもっと
Down, smile more...
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓落等上等
Down, falling from grace...
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓は？
Down, what?!
ウザったきらいだもうイヤイヤイヤってのアイアイヤってもアイアイヤってもアイアイヤパパン
Annoying, dazzling, I've had enough, no!
ウザった限界だもうイヤイヤイヤってのアイアイヤって怒号アアアアウ！
Annoying, limit reached, I've had enough, no!
アイもっともっともっともっともっともっともっと熱唱
Hey, more, more, more... passionate!
アイもっともっともっともっともっともっともっと合唱
Hey, more, more, more... chorus!
アイもっともっともっともっともっともっともっと絶唱
Hey, more, more, more... belting!
アイ not not not not not not 戦争
Not, not, not, not, not, not war!
どう逆らっても真摯です居た堪れない生た生た生た生た生た生た産まれないぱぁーん
No matter how you go against it, it's sincere, unbearable!
ウザったきらいだもうイヤイヤイヤってのアイアイヤってもアイアイヤってもアイアイヤパパン
Annoying, dazzling, I've had enough, no!
ウザった限界だもうイヤイヤイヤってのアイアイヤって怒号アアアアウ！
Annoying, limit reached, I've had enough, no!
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓立ち上がって
Down, stand up...
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓笑いっそ
Down, smile!
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓落等上等
Down, falling from grace...
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓はい。
Down, yes.
↓ダ↓ダ↓ダダ↓DOWN↓は？
Down, what?!
ラブちゃん来てくれてありがとう！
Left, Chan, come and give us a hug!
来たぞー！
Came!
なんか歩くなくない？
Doesn't it look a little walkable?
ペコラさん来たよ。
Pekora-san is here.
今日何の日か分かってるの？
What's going on today?
あ！
Ah!
アメ！
Ame!
アメおめでとう！
Ame, congratulations!
Congratulations!
おめでとうございます！
ていうか、デビュー何周年なの？
Is this the anniversary of when you debuted?
呼んでくれて、あざっす！
Call me, Azu!
ちょっと来ないだのこの人。何に殺すの。
Wait, how is it that this person just kills people?
おめでとうございます！
Hey, congratulations!
初めてのさ、これ、3Dコラプだから、ちゃんと写真撮っていい？
This is the first time we've taken a 3D photo together.
あ、もうしゃあない。
Well, can't be helped.
じゃあみんな、撮ってペコなと！
Then everyone, say cheese!
あ、かわいい！
Aww, cute!
ほら、ちっちゃってかわいいペコだね。
Look, it's so small and cute, Pekora.
これはちょっと別ですわ、これ写真。なんか君みたいな顔。
It's different, this photo looks like you're licking me.
わかりませんわ、写真。
I don't know, your photos...
やばい、そろそろお時間みたいペコだよ。
It's dangerous, it's about time.
はや！急いで！早く行くよ！
Hurry! Let's go quickly!
待って、どこどこどこどこ、ペコラさん！
Wait, Pekora-san!
ブンブンブン ブンブンブン
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom...
インフルエンサー (HEY!HEY!HEY!)
Influencer (Hey! Hey! Hey!)
いつだって 知ら ない うち に 僕は 見回して いる (何度 も)
Before I even knew it, I was looking around (so many times)
君 が どこ で 何 を し て いる か 気 に なっ て しまう ん だ (落ち着かなくなる)
Where you are and what you're doing, I can't help but wonder (I can't stay calm)
声 くらい 掛けれ ば いい 誰も が 思う だろ う (できない)
Everyone thinks, "Just say a word" (No way)
君 が いる 場所 が わかっ たら 僕 に は 地図 に なる ん だ
If I know where you are, it becomes a map for me
外見 より も もっと 深く 恋 は 内面 覗く こと さ
More than appearance, love is about looking inside
君らしさに浸ってしまう 切なさがもの足りない
I'm drowning in your uniqueness, missing that poignant feeling
僕は叫んでいる
I'm shouting
ブンブンブン ブンブンブン
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom
インフルエンサー
Influencer
HEY! HEY! HEY!
いつだって 知らないうちに
Always, before I knew it,
僕は見ーまわしている
I'm looking around...
君がどこで何を してーるか
Where and what you might be doing
気になってしまうんだ
I can't help wondering.
声くらい掛けれーばいい
You'd think I could just speak to you,
誰もが 思うだろう
anyone would think that.
君がいる場所が わかったら
Once I know the place where you are,
僕には 地図になるんだ
it becomes a map for me.
気配以上 会話未遂
More than a presence, attempted conversation,
恋はいつも よそよそしい
love is always so distant.
胸騒ぎが 聴こえないように
So I can't hear my heart pounding,
世界から言葉なんか 消えてしまえばいい
I wish all words would vanish from the world.
地球と太陽みたいに 光と影が生まれて
Like the earth and the sun, light and shadow are born,
君を探してばかり 距離は縮まらない
always searching for you, but the distance never closes.
HEY! HEY! HEY!
重力 引力 惹かれて
Gravity, attraction, drawn in,
1から10まで君次第
from 1 to 10 it's all up to you.
存在するだけで 影響を与えてる
Just existing, you exert your influence.
インフルエンサー
Influencer!
ブンブンブン ブンブンブン
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom
インフルエンサー
Influencer
HEY! HEY! HEY!
その他の誰かなんて 全然興味ないけど
Anyone else I have zero interest in,
君が何を考えてるか 知りたくてしょうがない
but what you're thinking I desperately want to know.
ミュージックやファッションとか 映画や小説とか
Music or fashion, movies or novels,
お気に入りのもの 手にすれば 時間を共有できるんだ
if I get your favorites, we can share the time.
外見よりももっと深く 恋は内面覗くことさ
Deeper than looks, love is peering into the inside,
君らしさに溺れてしまう 切なさがもの足りない
drowning in your uniqueness, the ache is not enough.
僕は叫んでいる
I am shouting out.
自転と公転みたいに 意識と愛が回って
Like rotation and revolution, consciousness and love spin,
君を想い続ける 宇宙の中心さ
continuing to think of you, you are the center of the universe.
HEY! HEY! HEY!
どんなに離れていたって 働きかけるその力
No matter how far apart, that force working on me,
もし君がなくなったら 僕は僕じゃなくなる
if you were gone, I wouldn't be myself.
インフルエンサー
Influencer!
地球と太陽みたいに 光と影が生まれて
Like the earth and the sun, light and shadow are born,
君を探してばかり 距離は縮まらない
always searching for you, but the distance never closes.
HEY! HEY! HEY!
重力 引力 惹かれて
Gravity, attraction, drawn in,
1から10まで君次第
from 1 to 10 it's all up to you.
存在するだけで 影響を与えてる
Just existing, you exert your influence.
インフルエンサー
Influencer!
ブンブンブン ブンブンブン
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom
インフルエンサー
Influencer
どんなに離れていたって 働きかけるその力
No matter how far apart, that force working on me,
もし君がなくなったら 僕は僕じゃなくなる
if you were gone, I wouldn't be myself.
インフルエンサー
Influencer!
ブンブンブン ブンブンブン
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom
インフルエンサー
Influencer
HEY! HEY! HEY!
いつだって 知らないうちに 僕は見ーまわしている
Always, before I knew it, I'm looking around...
君がどこで何を してーるか 気になってしまうんだ
Where and what you might be doing, I can't help wondering.
声くらい掛けれーばいい 誰もが 思うだろう
You'd think I could just speak to you, anyone would think that.
君がいる場所が わかったら 僕には 地図になるんだ
Once I know the place where you are, it becomes a map for me.
気配以上 会話未遂 恋はいつも よそよそしい
More than a presence, attempted conversation, love is always so distant.
胸騒ぎが 聴こえないように 世界から言葉なんか 消えてしまえばいい
So I can't hear my heart pounding, I wish all words would vanish from the world.
地球と太陽みたいに 光と影が生まれて
Like the earth and the sun, light and shadow are born,
君を探してばかり 距離は縮まらない
always searching for you, but the distance never closes.
HEY! HEY! HEY!
重力 引力 惹かれて 1から10まで君次第
Gravity, attraction, drawn in, from 1 to 10 it's all up to you.
存在するだけで 影響を与えてる
Just existing, you exert your influence.
インフルエンサー
Influencer!
ブンブンブン ブンブンブン ブンブンブン ブンブンブン
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom
インフルエンサー
Influencer
HEY! HEY! HEY!
ブンブンブン ブンブンブン ブンブンブン ブンブンブン
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom
インフルエンサー
Influencer
HEY! HEY! HEY!
二人ともありがとうございました！
Thank you both so much!
久しぶりに、久しぶりに、どうだった？
It's been so long, how was it?
え、なんかめちゃめちゃ久しぶりじゃない？
Eh, isn't it super long since last time?
久しぶりですね！
It has been a while!
だって、この前はなんかすごい絶叫しようぜ部屋からみたいなゲームやってきりな気がする
Because last time we played that "let's scream" escape room game or something.
なんでこんな期間空いたの？え、なんで？
Why was there such a long gap? Eh, why?
あー、はいはいはい！はいはい、確かに！確かに！そう！
Ah, yes yes yes! Yes yes, true! True! Yeah!
忘れちゃってるよ、これ！忘れちゃってるよ！
We forgot about it! We forgot!
なんかさ、でもさ、トワ様的には遊びたいなって思ってるよ？
Like, but Towa-sama, you think you want to play?
本当に？なんか持ってなさそう、プレボ
Really? Doesn't look like you have it, pre-orders.
なさそうね！
Doesn't seem like it!
なんか寂しい！寂しいな！寂しい！
It's kind of lonely! So lonely! Lonely!
なんかさ、3人でさ、なんかよくさ、じゃあもうあれだよねこれ、ペボ、ペボになっちゃうね
Like, the three of us, we often, well, then it's that, Pe-bo, it becomes Pe-bo.
ペボになっちゃうね！と、と、と！
It becomes Pe-bo! To, to, to!
いや、やっぱペボットでほらね！色々ほら、ほんとに？
No, as expected with Pebot, see! Various things, really?
ほらね、なんか3人でさ、なんかアンケートも募集ベコだもんね
See, like the three of us, we're also recruiting questionnaires, Peko.
そうだね！アンケートでね、ね、決めるんだろ？
That's right! Decided by questionnaire, right?
待って待って！アンケート決ればなんでも
Wait wait! Whatever is decided by questionnaire.
待って待って！
Wait wait!
え、二人とも本当にありがとうね！またね！バイバイ！バイバイ！
Eh, thank you both so much! See you again! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
バイバイ！またね！バイバイ！バイバイ！
Bye-bye! See you! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
帰り道は遠回りしたくなる
I want to take the long way home.
好きだった… この場所…
I loved this place...
やめられない漫画を途中で閉じて
Closing the manga I couldn't put down midway,
顔を上げて気づくように
raising my head so I would notice,
居心地いい日向もいつの間にか
the comfortable sunny spot before I knew it
影になって黄昏る
had turned into shadow at twilight.
君と… 会って…
Meeting you...
過ぎる時間忘れるくらい夢中で話した
talking so earnestly I forgot the passing time.
僕の夢は ここではないどこかへ
My dream is to go somewhere else, not here.
帰り道は 帰り道は
For the road home, the road home,
遠回したくなるよ
I want to take a roundabout way.
どこを行けば どこに着くか?
If I go somewhere, where will I arrive?
過去の道なら迷うことがないから
Because on a path from the past, I'd never get lost.
弱虫 (弱虫...)
Coward (Coward...)
新しい世界へ
Head towards the new world!
今行きたい 行きたい 行きたい 行きたい
Now I want to go, want to go, want to go, want to go,
強くなりたい
I want to become strong!
Oh... 好きだった... この場所...
Oh... I loved this place...
Oh...
Oh... 一歩目 踏み出そう
Oh... Let's take the first step!
街灯りが寂しくふと感じるのは 見慣れた景色と違うから
Streetlights suddenly feeling lonely because it's different from the familiar scenery.
いつもの高架線が見えなくなって どこにいるかわからない
Not seeing the usual overhead wires, I don't know where I am.
人は誰も変わることに慣れていなくて昨日と同じように今日も明日も ここにいたくなるんだ
People aren't used to change, wanting to stay here today and tomorrow just like yesterday.
知らない道 知らない道 あと何回 歩けるだろう
The unknown road, the unknown road, how many more times can I walk it?
夢の方へ 愛の方へ 風は道を選んだりはしないよ
Toward my dreams, toward love—the wind doesn't choose its path.
ONE WAYの標識でも 行くんだ 行くんだ 行くんだ 行くんだ
Even with a ONE-WAY sign, I'll go, I'll go, I'll go, I'll go!
帰れなくても…
Even if I can't return...
君と離れるのは悲しいけれど 大事な別れだ
Being apart from you is sad, but it's an important farewell.
もっともっと広い世界を知らなきゃいけない
I need to know a much, much wider world.
いつかきっと 違う道を選んだ意味 輝く未来のため互いにわかるだろう
Someday, for the sake of a sparkling future, we'll understand the meaning of choosing different paths.
風のように 風のように 思うままに生きてみよう
Like the wind, like the wind, let's live as we please.
過去がどんな眩しくても 未来はもっと眩しいかもしれない
No matter how dazzling the past is, the future might be even brighter.
帰り道は 帰り道は 遠回りしたくなるよ
For the road home, the road home, I want to take a roundabout way.
どこを行けば どこに着くか? 過去の道なら迷うことがないから
If I go somewhere, where will I arrive? Because on a path from the past, I'd never get lost.
弱虫 新しい世界へ 今行きたい 行きたい 行きたい 行きたい 強くなりたい
Coward—head towards the new world! Now I want to go, want to go, want to go, want to go, I want to become strong!
Oh... 好きだった... この場所...
Oh... I loved this place...
Oh... 大切な... 想い出...
Oh... Precious... memories...
Oh... 好きだった... この場所...
Oh... I loved this place...
てこちゃん！ あずちゃん、おめでとー！
Azu-chan! Azu-chan, congratulations!
ありがとう！ ありがとうぺこー！
Thank you! Thank you, Peko!
いやぁ、こちらこそ来てくれてありがとう！
Man, thank you so much for coming!
こちらこそ！ こんな素敵なライブに呼んでくれてありがとう！
No, thank you! Thank you so much for inviting me to such a wonderful live!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
これ、あの、あずちゃんって呼んでくれたきっかけ、なんですっけ？
Wait, what was the reason you started calling me "Azu-chan"?
あー！ いええええい！
Ah! Yay!
いやでもぺこらは本当にあずちゃんと歌コラボをしたくて
But you know, Peko really wanted to do a singing collaboration with Azu-chan,
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
まさか受けてくれるなんて、叶った、叶った！
and never expected you would accept. It came true!
これからも誘ってもいいってことですか？
Does this mean I can invite you again in the future?
もちろん！ よっしゃ！ じゃあ2人で仲良く…仲直り？
Of course! Yes! Then the two of us can get along... make up?
帰ろう、ぺこら！
Let's head home, Pekora!
ばいばーい！
Bye-bye!
駐車場の猫は あくびをしながら
While the cat in the parking lot yawns,
今日も一日を過ごしてゆく
It goes on spending yet another day.
何も変わらない
Nothing ever changes,
穏やかな街並み
In this peaceful town.
みんな夏が来だって浮かれ気分なのに
Everyone's excited that summer has come,
君は一人冴えない顔をしてるね
Yet you look so down and out, all alone.
そうだ君に見せたいものがあるんだ
That's right, there's something I want to show you—
大きな五時半の夕焼け
A big, 5:30 sunset.
子供の頃と同じように
Just like when we were kids,
海も空も雲も僕等でさえも
Painting the sea, sky, clouds, and even us...
染めてゆくから...
With its colors...
この長い長い下り坂を
Down this long, long slope,
君を自転車の後ろに乗せて
With you on the back of my bicycle,
ブレーキいっぱい握りしめて
Gripping the brakes with all my might,
ゆっくりゆっくり下ってく
Coasting slowly, slowly down.
君の胸で泣かない
I won't cry on your chest,
君に胸焦がさない
Nor will my heart burn for you.
I'm looking for a perfect sky
背中までかもしかの塔
A gazelle-like tower reaching my back,
熱い夏を凍らせてよ
Freeze this scorching summer!
I'm looking for a perfect sky
君の胸で泣かない
I won't cry on your chest,
君に胸焦がさない
Nor will my heart burn for you.
I'm looking for a perfect sky
YO! SAY、夏が胸を刺激する
YO! SAY, summer stimulates the chest,
ナマ足 魅惑のマーメイド
Bare legs, the enchanting mermaid.
出す とこ 出して たわわ に なったら
Show what you've got when they become full,
宝物 (ホンモノ) の 恋 は やれ 爽快 っ
Real treasure love is exhilarating!
妖精たちが夏を刺激する
Fairies stimulate the summer,
恋にかまけてお留守番になるのも
Being absent because you're caught up in love,
ダイスケ的にもオールオッケー！
Even Daisuke says it's all okay!
一人寝の夜に you can say good bye
On lonely nights, you can say goodbye.
奥の方まで乾く間もないほど
Before you dry up completely inside...
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
You and the end of summer, future dreams, great hopes I won't forget.
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを 信じて
Believing we'll meet again in August ten years from now.
最高の思い出を...
The best memories...
出逢いはふとした瞬間 帰り道の交差点で
We met in a fleeting moment at the crosswalk on the way home.
声をかけてくれたね 「一緒に帰ろう」
You spoke to me and said, "Let's go home together."
君とてれくさそうに
With you, looking so bashful,
カバンで顔を隠しながら
hiding your face behind your bag—
本当はとてもとても嬉しかったよ
the truth is, I was so, so happy.
ああ 花火が夜空綺麗に咲いて ちょっとセツナク
Ah, fireworks bloom so brightly in the night sky, a bit bittersweet.
ああ 風が時間とともに流れる
Ah, the wind flows away along with time.
嬉しくって楽しくって冒険も色々したね 二人の秘密の基地の中
We had so many happy, fun adventures together inside our secret base.
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
At the end of summer with you, our future dreams and big hopes, never forgetting.
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを 信じて
Believing we can meet again in August ten years from now.
君が最後まで心から「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと知っていたよ
I knew that, until the very end, you were shouting "Thank you" from the bottom of your heart.
涙をこらえて笑顔でさようなら切ないよね 最高な思い出を...
Holding back tears, smiling to say goodbye is so heartbreaking... Such great memories...
ああ 夏休みもあと少しで終わっちゃうから
Ah, summer break will be over soon,
ああ 太陽と月仲良くして
Ah, I hope the sun and moon get along well.
悲しくって寂しくって喧嘩も色々したね 二人の秘密の基地の中
We had so many sad, lonely times and various fights inside our secret base.
君と夏の終わり将来の夢大きな希望忘れない
At the end of summer with you, our future dreams and big hopes, never forgetting.
10年後の8月また出会えるのを信じて
Believing we can meet again in August ten years from now.
さいごの おもいでを
Our final memories...
突然の
Suddenly...
転校で
transferring schools,
どうしようもなく
feeling so helpless,
手紙書くよ電話もするよ忘れないでね僕のことを
I'll write letters, I'll call you, so don't forget me.
いつまでも二人の基地の中
Forever inside our base.
君と夏の終わり ずっと話して 夕日を見てから 星を眺め
At the end of summer with you, talking all along, watching the sunset, then gazing at the stars.
君の頬を流れた 涙をずっと忘れない
I'll never forget the tears that flowed down your cheek.
君が最後まで 大きく手を振ってくれたこと きっと忘れない
I'll never forget how you waved your hand so big until the very end.
だから こうして 夢の中 で ずっと永遠に
And that's why, inside our dreams, forever and ever.
君と夏の終わり将来の夢大きな希望忘れない
At the end of summer with you, our future dreams and big hopes, never forgetting.
10年後の8月また出会えるのを信じて
Believing we can meet again in August ten years from now.
君が最後まで心から「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと知っていたよ
I knew that, until the very end, you were shouting "Thank you" from the bottom of your heart.
涙をこらえて笑顔でさようなら切ないよね
Holding back tears, smiling to say goodbye is so heartbreaking...
最高な思い出を...
Such great memories...
なんだこのクオリティの高さは
What is with this crazy high quality?!
いやめっちゃ喋っているの
Man, everyone's talking so much!
ぺこらちゃん、3周年おめでとう！
Pekora-chan, happy 3rd anniversary!
いやみんな来てくれて本当ありがとう！
Seriously, thank you all so much for coming!
いや夏のメドレーめちゃくちゃ斬新でさ
Man, that summer medley was super fresh and novel!
みんなでねそれぞれ歌いたい曲とかでもねぺこらはね
We each got to pick songs we wanted to sing, and for Pekora...
シークレットベースもすごい良かったんだけど、メグミンの人...
Secret Base was really great, but Megumin's...
いやそれ違うから！めぐみんて誰だよ！
Wait, that's wrong! Who's Megumin?!
これからもよろしくおねがいします！
Please continue to support us from now on!
じゃあもうぺこらの配信おわりすか？
So is Pekora's stream ending now?
違う違う違うまだ！この後にもうちょびっとだけあるからペコらから！
No, no, no, not yet! There's a tiny bit more after this from Pekora!
や、でもさすがに告知で終わりか？
Well, but is it really just announcements?
え、でも、えっ？ なんだペコだよ！
Eh, but, eh? What kind of Pekora is that!
まあ、告知だよ、やっぱな。
Well, it's announcements, after all.
どうかな？ なんか、そんな...
I wonder? Somehow, like that...
なんか、あんな感じかな？
Like, that kind of feeling?
あるかもしれないペコだから。
There might be, because it's Pekora.
え？ みんな納得納得できないよ！
Eh? Everyone, we can't accept this!
できないよ！ もうみんなで！
We can't! Everyone together!
見て、ほら！ 楽しみ足りないよ！
Look, see! We haven't had enough fun!
じゃ、またみんな遊ぼうペコな。
Well then, let's play together again, Peko.
またねー！ ばいばーい！
See you later! Bye-bye!
落ちた方がいいか？ あっ、落ちろ！
Should I log off? Ah, log off!
落ちろ！
Log off!
手荒なわけで、告知タイムいこうともペコー！
In a rough way, let's go to the announcement time, Peko!
はい、そしたらなさ、今日は告知が二つあります。
Right, then, today we have two announcements.
みんな、聞く準備はできてるペコですか？
Everyone, are you ready to listen, Peko?
じゃあ、さっそく、多分もう待てないと思うペコだから、告知しちゃうペコ！
Well then, right away, since you probably can't wait anymore, I'll announce it, Peko!
1つ目は、こちら、どーん！
The first one is, here, ta-da!
兎田ぺこら3周年記念グッズが発売になるぺこー！ やー！
Usada Pekora 3rd Anniversary merchandise is going on sale, Peko! Yay!
まあ、見て分かると思うペコだけど、今回のグッズは
Well, I think you can tell by looking, but this time's goods
テーマ、冒険、ま、勇者、そんな感じになってるペコだけど
theme is adventure, well, hero, it's becoming that kind of feel, but
なんできこんな感じになってるかは、まあ、次の次の告知で分かるペコだから、ちょっと考えてみてペコな。
Why it's like this, well, you'll understand in the next-next announcement, so think about it a bit, Peko.
そしたらな、グッズの紹介をしていこうと思うペコ！
Then, let's go ahead and introduce the goods, Peko!
まず1つ目は、タペストリー！ これ、クロガネ先生にね、描いていただきました。
First is the tapestry! This was drawn for us by Kurogane-sensei.
そして、兎田ぺこら＆野うさぎドットラバーキーホルダー！
And, Usada Pekora & Nousagi dot rubber keychain!
ロングタオル、ガジェットケースの4つとなってるペコ！
Long towel, gadget case—making 4 items, Peko!
こちらはね、あのフルセットを買っていただいた方限定で、クロガネ先生描き下ろしのポストカードがついてくるペコなので、ぜひぜひ皆さんお手に取っていただきたいと、おもうペコ！
As for this, those who buy the full set will get a postcard newly drawn by Kurogane-sensei, so everyone please definitely pick it up, Peko!
そして、ま、2つ目の告知になっちゃうペコだけど、ま、分かってるよね？ 多分でも分かってるペコだよね？
And, well, it's going to be the second announcement, but well, you know, right? You probably know, right?
さあ、こちら、どーん！ 兎田ぺこら3曲目のオリジナル楽曲「ララララビット！！」が発売になるぺこ！ やー！
Now, here, ta-da! Usada Pekora's 3rd original song "RaRaRa Rabbit!!" is going on release, Peko! Yay!
本日の24時からリリースとなっていますペコですので、たくさん聞いてくれると嬉しいペコです。
It is scheduled to be released starting at 24:00 today, Peko, so I'd be happy if you listen to it a lot.
なんと、作詞作曲、ナユタン星人さんです！ ありがとうございます！
And what's more, lyrics and composition by Nayutalien-san! Thank you very much!
えっ？ なに？ 早く聴けないかって？
Eh? What? You can't listen to it sooner?
はあ、そんなわがままな子もいるペコなと思ったから、聞けちゃいますナイトこのあとオリゾン歌うペコなので、お楽しみだペコ！
Ha, thinking there might be such selfish kids, Peko, you can hear it right after this because I'll be singing Horizon, so look forward to it!
手荒なわけで、準備してくるペコね！ ばいばーい！
In a rough way, get ready, Peko! Bye-bye!
旅立つ冒険 そしてインドアの神話へ――
Setting off on an adventure, and into indoor mythology...
最大級のラララララビット！！
The ultimate Ra-Ra-Ra-Ra-Ra Rabbit!!
最序盤のスライムにビビるのが大概なマイライフ
Getting scared of a slime at the very beginning is my usual life
ワン・トゥ・スリーで繋がったセカイに愛があふれだす
In a world connected by 1-2-3, love overflows
8bitに感じるドキドキ
Feeling the heartbeat in 8-bit
2Dのラブじゃダメですか？
Is 2D love not good enough?
運ゲー状態ふざけんじゃねぇぞ
Don't mess with me, acting like it's RNG
レベルアップして超えてやるぁ！
I'll level up and overcome it!
夢に見てるファンファーれの音
The sound of the fanfare I've been dreaming of
乱数調整 一転攻勢 一点突破 想定外も ロマンスの過程――
Random adjustment, turnaround, breakthrough, the unexpected too are part of romance...
ラヴィラヴィ ちいさなビットで でっかいアイを交信中！
Love-it, love-it, communicating big love into tiny bits!
ちょっと沼っても許してね？
Forgive me even if I get a little too hooked, right?
いつだって愛は非効率！
Love is always inefficient!
jumpin' jumpin' 跳ねるハートを捕まえて置いてね！
Jumpin' jumpin', catch that bouncing heart and keep it!
二兎なんて追わないで トゥルーエンドになるまで
Don't chase two rabbits until we reach the true end
最大級のラララララビット！！
The ultimate Ra-Ra-Ra-Ra-Ra Rabbit!!
人生とかけて無理ゲーと解く どちらもクリアがみえません！
Comparing life to an impossible game, neither has a clear ending in sight!
このラブって状態異常をとく アイテムはどこで買えますか！？
Where can I buy an item to cure this "love" status ailment?!
救済も！説明も！足りない！クソゲー！！ いや、足りないのわたしのINT！？
No salvation! No explanation! Not enough! Shitty game!! No, what's not enough is my INT?!
まあ、どんな難所も越えてやるけど そのまえに誰かいい案ありますか？
Well, I'll overcome any difficult spot, but before that, does anyone have a good idea?
ちゃんと届いてる あなたのエール
Your cheers are reaching me properly
一進一退 八方塞がり 絶体絶命 大失敗も サクセスの序章――
Step by step, trapped on all sides, desperate situations and huge failures too are the prologue to success...
ラヴィラヴィ ちいさなビットで でっかいセカイ躍進中
Love-it, love-it, making a leap in a big world with tiny bits
だってあなたとしたい
'Cause I want to do it with you,
私を見てほしいのよ
I want you to look at me,
よそ見しないでね
so don't look away, okay?
不器用でも愛してね
Even if I'm clumsy, love me,
もっと跳べるから
'cause I can jump even higher!
ラヴィラヴィ まだまだあなたとでっかいアイを更新中！
Rabbi, rabbi, still updating our huge love together!
暴走しちゃったら制してね？
If I run wild, keep me in check, okay?
だって愛は非常識！
'Cause love defies common sense!
もっともっと跳ねてたいからずっとそばで見ていてね！
I want to bounce more and more, so stay right by my side and watch!
どんな想いでもくださいな
Give me any feelings you have,
月まで届くくらいに
enough to reach all the way to the moon,
最大級のラビット！ララララララヴィ
a top-tier rabbit! La-la-la-la-la-rabbi!
もっとしたいの！ラビット！ララララララヴィ
I want more! Rabbit! La-la-la-la-la-rabbi!
ぺこーらもついに3周年ぺこ！長いようで、あっという間だな〜
Pekora is finally celebrating her 3rd anniversary, peko! It feels long, yet went by in a flash~
ここまでこれたのは、応援してくれたみんなのおかげ！
Making it this far is all thanks to everyone who supported me!
これからもみんなと一緒に笑って10年、100年ずっといたい！
I want to keep laughing and be together with everyone for 10 years, 100 years, forever!
4年目のペコラストーリーも共に歩んでね？
Walk together with me through my 4th-year Pekora story too, okay?
もっともっとそばにいてぺこー！バイバーイ！
Stay by my side more and more, peko! Bye-bye!